<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Pro-cantabrigian hypsidolichocephalism</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://boustrophedon.github.io/</id><updated>2014-09-12T02:24:25-04:00</updated><entry><title>This will make some people mad</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/this-will-make-some-people-mad.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-12T02:24:25-04:00</updated><author><name>Harry Stern</name></author><id>tag:https://boustrophedon.github.io,2014-09-12:this-will-make-some-people-mad.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the shower today I came up with a pretty good metaphor for javascript vs. dart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You live in a desert. It is a no-fun, boring place. One day, someone from the Eich Construction Co. decides to make a playground. However, instead of a playground they end up making a minefield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone rejoices and declares this to be the best thing ever. About 10-15 years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People spend their time navigating the minefield, learning all the quirks and blowing themselves up regularly. Some people write books about how to navigate it (The Good Parts), others try to carpet or paint over the parts that are unsafe (CoffeeScript, TypeScript). People acquire Stockholm Syndrome regarding the playground/minefield and try to convince other people how fun it is.
"Oh, avoiding the mines is a great way to increase your acrobatic ability."
"You know, if you squint closely the minefield has some characteristics of a &lt;em&gt;functional&lt;/em&gt; playground."
"Look at this sandcastle I build directly on top of an active mine! I'm sure there won't be any problems if I try and make it bigger."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people even take some of the mines and put them in their own &lt;strike&gt;servers&lt;/strike&gt; backyards and claim it is the best thing since sliced bread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then this company GOOG Development Inc. comes along and some of them see these people being blown up, and decide to try something new. They build this nice big platform above the minefield, so you can't even step on it unless you really want to. It has actual attractions, like a water slide and a merry-go-round, because GOOG Dev. Inc. has lots of money to throw around. They develop a home version so you can put it in your &lt;strike&gt;server&lt;/strike&gt; backyard and it is faster and more efficient in benchmarks than the original mines. (okay I gave up on the metaphor here)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's really nice, but people have learned to love their minefield and continue to tell themselves that it's great. Why? WHY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I couldn't think of a good way to fit it in, but the guys who developed the v8 engine that node runs on and such? they are the guys who started dart and made the dart vm faster than v8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this sparks lots of flame wars in the Hackathon Hackers group.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Dart"></category><category term="Dartlang"></category><category term="Javascript"></category><category term="jimmies being rustled"></category></entry><entry><title>How to make daily backups with rdiff-backup and systemd</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/how-to-make-daily-backups-with-rdiff-backup-and-systemd.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-12T02:02:54-04:00</updated><author><name>Harry Stern</name></author><id>tag:https://boustrophedon.github.io,2014-09-12:how-to-make-daily-backups-with-rdiff-backup-and-systemd.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other day I was talking to one of my friends and he mentioned how he lost a hard drive recently and consequently all of his stuff. I realized that, although I had bought a backup hard drive a little while ago, I hadn't done more than a couple backups with it when I felt like it. So I decided that I would finally set up regular backups of my home directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd looked briefly at backup solutions before and thought that &lt;a href="http://savannah.nongnu.org/projects/rdiff-backup"&gt;rdiff-backup&lt;/a&gt; seemed like a good choice. I also want to do snapshots at some point either with straight-up rsync or rsnapshot, but for now just the differential backups are probably fine. So I chose rdiff-backup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One easily-solved problem I encountered was that I have large data files that I don't have space to back up and that aren't super necessary to back up in the first place. However, I wanted to keep track of the files. So I'm using &lt;code&gt;rdiff-backup --exclude&lt;/code&gt; to exclude those directories, and then writing the output of &lt;code&gt;ls -lLR&lt;/code&gt; in those directories to a file to keep track of what's in them. Since the -l option tells us the modified times, I didn't think it was necessary to write the listing files out into my actual home directory and then have that be part of the backup. EDIT: On second thought, it actually is necessary to do so. If, for example, the entire directory we're saving the listing of was deleted, and then the backup script ran again, the listing would be overwritten with nothing and it would be pointless. So we need to do the listing before running the background and it needs to output to a directory that is going to be backed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I combined these two steps into a python script that prints some information about what it's doing and then runs the commands. I always prefer python scripts to bash because you don't have to worry about escaping, or portability, or unreadability, or any of the other problems one encounters with shell scripting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other half of the backup problem is actually running the backups. Putting a backup command in your crontab isn't the best idea for a desktop or laptop because it might be scheduled to run while your computer is off, resulting in a missed backup. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anacron"&gt;Anacron&lt;/a&gt; is traditionally the solution to this: it runs cron jobs on a hourly/daily/monthly/whatever basis and, more importantly, will run jobs that were missed while the computer was off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I knew that systemd somewhat-recently gained support for doing cron-like things, and I knew that if I used systemd and wrote a unit file to run the backups, I could get the output easily and nicely into systemd's journal, making it easy to check that backups are running. If I put it in cron or anacron, which on my system are both covered by cronie, the output from my backup script would be mixed together with the other cronjobs' outputs. (I think.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I wrote a simple .service unit file that runs the python script I wrote as a oneshot, and then wrote a .timer file which tells systemd to run the corresponding .service file with the same name daily (&lt;code&gt;OnCalendar=daily&lt;/code&gt;) and to run it ASAP if we missed the last time it was supposed to run (&lt;code&gt;Persistent=true&lt;/code&gt;). The service file also has some options to set the nice value to 19 (the lowest priority) and lower the IO priority. (&lt;code&gt;Nice=19&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;IOSchedulingClass=2&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;IOSchedulingPriority=7&lt;/code&gt;) These were mostly copied from &lt;a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Systemd/cron_functionality"&gt;this page on the arch linux wiki&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure to delete the in-line comments; they will cause errors if you try to actually use them as they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked into using systemd user sessions to run these, but it seemed a bit complicated to set up and I wasn't entirely sure what the benefit was. Furthermore, I might use this script to do backups of /etc or something in the future, which would mean I wouldn't use a user session anyway. So instead I have the unit run as my own user (&lt;code&gt;User=username&lt;/code&gt;) and copied the .service and .timer files into &lt;code&gt;/etc/systemd/system/&lt;/code&gt;. I copied the python script that does the backups to &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin/backup-scripts/&lt;/code&gt;, though you could just leave it in &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin/&lt;/code&gt; just the same. The last step to make everything work is to enable the timer unit with something like &lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl enable my-backup.timer&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's probably irrational, but I feel a bit nervous making my script and unit files public even though the worst/best thing that would probably happen would be someone pointing out a way to make them better. Email me or something if you want to see them, I guess? that feels really lame.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="backups"></category><category term="rdiff-backup"></category><category term="systemd"></category><category term="journalctl"></category><category term="cron"></category><category term="anacron"></category></entry><entry><title>I went to an IGDA NJ meetup and it was cool</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/i-went-to-an-igda-nj-meetup-and-it-was-cool.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-03T02:54:45-04:00</updated><author><name>Harry Stern</name></author><id>tag:https://boustrophedon.github.io,2014-07-03:i-went-to-an-igda-nj-meetup-and-it-was-cool.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, July 1st, I went to the IGDA NJ arcade demo meetup thing instead of studying for my differential equations final on the 2nd. didn't do too well, oops. However, there were cool people there and there were some surprisingly cool games. More importantly, I talked to a few people who were at the very least interested in coming to talk to COGS. Everyone there was indie so I didn't even mention the word "sponsorship" and I wouldn't ask anyone there for money for COGS, but meeting people is always helpful because you can't predict who knows who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a bit unfortunate they went to a bar afterwards because Richard and I (I went with him and he drove) were pretty hungry and it would have been cool to hang out with the people there some more. It seems like it's a monthly-ish thing, and I got into the NYC IGDA group recently as well and it seems like they do stuff too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should advertise for speakers/sponsors in some of those groups as we get closer to the beginning of the semester and also confirmation from Rutgers that we will be an actual club. We could just post a simple google doc with "company name" "name" "contact info" "anything else" and like, my email address, but somehow that rubs me the wrong way. I guess I'd rather it be more personal, but at the same time I also want to advertise to the almost 900 people in the NYC IGDA facebook group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also Richard had the good (obvious, but the best ideas are the obvious ones) to make a COGS spreadsheet for contacts. Richard had a lot of good ideas. He should really be on the e-board. He's also a pretty good programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uh, I don't really have anything more I want to write right now but I feel like I should. Oh, he made the point that we should make the COGS demo game by just having a weekend game hackathon; get everyone into a room and make the game. Then probably do some cleanup so that we know how simple it can be. One or two people should do the architecture ahead of time so we just basically have to fill in the parts that we're going to fill in for the livecoding thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we should try out the livecoding idea to see if it actually works before doing it at the first meeting. yes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="COGS"></category><category term="IGDA"></category><category term="game development"></category><category term="networking or whatever"></category></entry><entry><title>More thoughts on COGS</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/more-thoughts-on-cogs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-03T02:26:14-04:00</updated><author><name>Harry Stern</name></author><id>tag:https://boustrophedon.github.io,2014-07-03:more-thoughts-on-cogs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I put the last post on the COGS Facebook group and Andrew made some good points, and I talked to V and Billy and they made similar points (those two also gave me other ideas which I will talk about later in this post). Basically, making a game that's big enough to be a group project is difficult to do during the semester for a variety of reasons, moreso if people don't have extrinsic motivation like getting a grade. So I don't think we're going to do a big club-wide game project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggestions that were made for other things to do: still make games, but on a smaller scale. Have mini-hackathons on the weekend where the goal is to make some small game that fits a theme. If the livecoding thing goes well (oh, by the way, I think we're doing to do a 2d tron game.) we can do more of those. I am a bit afraid that I will just end up awkwardly standing there. Hopefully I can get people to participate by seeding the audience with people who helped write the game in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that we definitely can't do is just gather people in a room and say "okay, now make games." That's not going to work. Anyone who could do that without needing any help probably already is and doesn't need someone to tell them. The people we want to get into the club are people who either don't know how to make games, and people whose CS abilities are good enough but they don't have artists to work with or realize that making games is fun or something. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we need to have events that focus on teaching people how to make games, and getting people who normally wouldn't consider trying to make games to try and make games. This includes getting artists and possibly musicians involved, and we need to follow up on leads in that direction as well. We have an entire art school; some of the people there must think that making video game art sounds cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly: food. We can't use the money Rutgers gives us (however that much ends up being. I would guess maybe $50? We can use it for Unreal Engine/Unity/whatever site licenses), but we can use money we get from outside sources for whatever we want, including getting pizza for talks/meetings. So, V and Billy suggested we use USACS' contact excel sheet and/or cold-email people who have some sort of stake in game development, e.g. Microsoft, and ask them to sponsor us/throw us money. They can send people to come give a talk or whatever. Oh look I just found &lt;a href="http://www.gamedevmap.com/index.php?query=New+York+City"&gt;this neat map&lt;/a&gt; that has a list of game development companies near NYC. If it's a game studio that actually makes games I don't really care if they give us money if they can send devs or someone down to talk to us, or if they let us come visit their offices or something. (and we could use Rutgers money for bus fare I think) Oh, interesting. I was looking at that list and apparently the &lt;a href="http://www.igda.org/"&gt;IGDA&lt;/a&gt;, the organization that originally ran the Global Game Jam, is in South Jersey. Oh hey, Rockstar's headquarters &lt;a href="http://www.rockstargames.com/careers/openings/rockstar-nyc"&gt;is in NYC&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely think if we get devs from some of these companies to come give talks on whatever and if even a few of them give us money, COGS will be on its way to becoming a legitimate-seeming club.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="COGS"></category><category term="game development"></category></entry><entry><title>Thoughts on what COGS should be</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/thoughts-on-what-cogs-should-be.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-03T02:26:14-04:00</updated><author><name>Harry Stern</name></author><id>tag:https://boustrophedon.github.io,2014-07-03:thoughts-on-what-cogs-should-be.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://cogs.club/"&gt;COGS&lt;/a&gt; (domain is new so it might not work yet) is the game development club I co-founded with some people at Rutgers. It used to be an informal seminar run by Lars and some other people based on a former professor's notes from a seminar class. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem I was kind of having was that I'm not really sure what COGS should "do". As in, the anime club watches anime, dance troupes practice for performances, USACS organizes the various events for CS majors, but what should COGS do? The first thing that comes to mind is, of course, "make games," when you put it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first few meetings, I have talked with other people about doing a sort of live-coding thing with whoever shows up. Basically, we're going to write a simple game over summer break, either a simple platformer or something like pole position. Then we're going to delete all the important parts, like the systems that do movement. (it will be in git so the completed version will be in a separate branch or something). The livecoding sessions will then consist of me (or whoever wants to) standing with a laptop hooked up to a projector, and taking suggestions from the crowd on how to implement the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought this was a good idea because we can then take suggestions from students who only sort of know Java from CS111 and 112; they don't necessarily need to know how to code their suggestions, as long as they can say something like "make a velocity vector and then add to the position each frame". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other ideas, i.e. for the rest of the semester, were basically that for the first part of the meeting someone would talk about a concept in game design or development, and then the rest of the meeting would be spent working individually or in groups on whatever people wanted. The problem with that model is that it doesn't really include artists in a meaningful way, or any other part of game development (e.g. design or story).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common suggestion at the one or two planning meetings we had before the semester ended was for everyone to work on a group project, and I'm starting to think that would be a good idea. In particular, when I realized the answer to "what does COGS do?" should be "make games," it seems fairly obvious. I have a moderately-ambitious game idea that I talked about with one or two other people, which I might write more about.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="COGS"></category><category term="game development"></category></entry><entry><title>Convolution</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/convolution.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-09T01:17:30-04:00</updated><author><name>Harry Stern</name></author><id>tag:https://boustrophedon.github.io,2014-06-09:convolution.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I'm reading the chapter "Signals and Systems" in PDIS, and since I took Professor Goodman's &lt;a href="http://www.math.rutgers.edu/courses/357/index.html?arch=Spring_2014"&gt;DSP course&lt;/a&gt; a lot of the material is familiar to me, but presented in a different way or context. It's very neat to see things presented in a slightly unfamiliar way and then realize "oh, I know this." It's somehow validating your knowledge or something and is gratifying in a weird but nice way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, this sentence really clicked for me in sort of mapping different intuitions to the same underlying idea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convolution is important because it tells us how to use a system's impulse response to find the output of the system to a given input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(at this point I continued reading)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exposition in this book is really quite good. Following from the previous statement, we determined that $e^{\omega t}$ is an eigenfunction of LTI systems by taking the convolution with the system's impulse response $h(x)$. (this sounds like a simple statement, or at least a succinct one, but it takes a bit of time to understand) Its eigenvalue is the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frequency_response"&gt;frequency response&lt;/a&gt; $\int h(\tau)e^{-\omega\tau}d\tau$. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fact reveals that one of the easiest types of functions to study with respect to LTI systems are the complex exponentials, since they pass through such systems unchanged except for complex scaling. If we can represent an input signal as a sum of these functions, then we can find the response of the system to each exponential individually, and then sum the responses together. The Fourier series and transform provide precisely the tools that decompose a signal into a sum of exponentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems like a very different way to arrive at Fourier series and transform than "let's decompose a function as a sum of sine and cosines because that sounds like fun". Basically, it gives us a reason why we might want to do such a thing a priori.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;script type= "text/javascript"&gt;
    if (!document.getElementById('mathjaxscript_pelican_#%@#$@#')) {
        var mathjaxscript = document.createElement('script');
        mathjaxscript.id = 'mathjaxscript_pelican_#%@#$@#';
        mathjaxscript.type = 'text/javascript';
        mathjaxscript.src = 'https:' == document.location.protocol
                ? 'https://c328740.ssl.cf1.rackcdn.com/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML'
                : 'http://cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML';
        mathjaxscript[(window.opera ? "innerHTML" : "text")] =
            "MathJax.Hub.Config({" +
            "    config: ['MMLorHTML.js']," +
            "    TeX: { extensions: ['AMSmath.js','AMSsymbols.js','noErrors.js','noUndefined.js'], equationNumbers: { autoNumber: 'AMS' } }," +
            "    jax: ['input/TeX','input/MathML','output/HTML-CSS']," +
            "    extensions: ['tex2jax.js','mml2jax.js','MathMenu.js','MathZoom.js']," +
            "    displayAlign: 'center'," +
            "    displayIndent: '0em'," +
            "    showMathMenu: true," +
            "    tex2jax: { " +
            "        inlineMath: [ ['$','$'] ], " +
            "        displayMath: [ ['$$','$$'] ]," +
            "        processEscapes: true," +
            "        preview: 'TeX'," +
            "    }, " +
            "    'HTML-CSS': { " +
            "        styles: { '.MathJax_Display, .MathJax .mo, .MathJax .mi, .MathJax .mn': {color: 'black ! important'} }" +
            "    } " +
            "}); ";
        (document.body || document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0]).appendChild(mathjaxscript);
    }
&lt;/script&gt;
</summary><category term="Principles of Digital Image Synthesis"></category><category term="convolution"></category></entry><entry><title>Principles of Digital Image Synthesis</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/principles-of-digital-image-synthesis.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-04T02:37:47-04:00</updated><author><name>Harry Stern</name></author><id>tag:https://boustrophedon.github.io,2014-06-04:principles-of-digital-image-synthesis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So one of the things I'm doing this summer is reading &lt;a href="http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=527570"&gt;Principles of Digital Image Synthesis&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://glassner.com/"&gt;Andrew Glassner&lt;/a&gt;. It's from 1995 which makes it almost 20 years old, but the fundamental mathematics don't change and it's quite comprehensive. I found it released freely &lt;a href="http://www.realtimerendering.com/blog/principles-of-digital-image-synthesis-now-free-for-download/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with "The Human Visual System and Color" for the first 100ish pages, covering "The Human Visual System", "Color Spaces", and "Displays". While I thought the chapter on how the eye works was interesting, I didn't really pay close attention to it, so that I feel like while I have a better understanding of how eyesight works than before, I don't think I could really explain it to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color spaces was too abstract for something that I thought should have been more visceral considering that it's color, but I think the main point of the chapter is that saying "it's just color, how difficult can it be?" is a very big mistake. There are problems with how a human perceives color, the unintuitiveness of the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CIE_XYZ"&gt;CIE XYZ color space&lt;/a&gt;, and more importantly the gamut that your monitor or printer is able to render. The chapter on color spaces also talks about the problem of perceptual uniformity; that is, in the XYZ color space, changes of equal distance are not equally perceptible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="MacAdam ellipse" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/f4/CIExy1931_MacAdam.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ellipses shown were reported to be of constant color in an &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MacAdam_ellipse"&gt;experiment&lt;/a&gt;, and they may or may not on your computer because the ellipses are enlarged and your computer may display the colors differently, so that there is a perceivable difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the part where I sort of stopped trying to understand 100% of what was going on. To fix this problem of perceptual (non-)uniformity, the CIE defined other spaces, L*a*b and L*u*v, which are transformations of the XYZ color space. I understand that the point is to make the spaces perceptually linear, but I don't really see what the formulas are doing or have any intuition for them other than the description that you can imagine a cylinder with the vertical axis being lightness and the angle and distance from the center being hue and saturation or whatever. Maybe if the pictures in the pdf were in color they would make sense. We actually have a copy of the book in the libraries at Rutgers; I should really just check the first volume out or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter on Displays was interesting but mostly about CRTs, which, obviously, aren't used very much after 20 years, so I don't really have much to say about it. There was material about the RGB color space and gamut mapping but I feel like I don't need to understand that 100% right now so I will continue on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote surprisingly more than I thought I would for what amounts to a summary of a cursory reading of the (if I may) more boring parts of a textbook.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Principles of Digital Image Synthesis"></category><category term="color systems"></category></entry><entry><title>First Post</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-03T21:53:59-04:00</updated><author><name>Harry Stern</name></author><id>tag:https://boustrophedon.github.io,2014-06-03:first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had several blogs over the years but I never really managed to consistently update one. The reason why I started this one is sort of stupid. I want to keep my streak on github, but I also want to spend time reading/learning computer graphics. However, I know that some days if I spend them reading I won't write any code, so the purpose of this blog is to make me actually learn something when I don't write code by forcing me to write about what I learned in order to keep the streak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure if this is a good idea. Regardless, it was also a chance to set up my github.io page. I'm using pelican because it was easier to install on arch than jekyll since I already had pip installed and didn't feel like figuring out rubygems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh I forgot about the name. The css is fucked right now and I might just change the theme completely, but it is "Pro-cantabrigian hypsidolichocephalism", which are just two random words I picked from /usr/share/dict/words. It doesn't mean anything. Well, technically the words have a meaning but it's not important.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>