<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Pro-cantabrigian hypsidolichocephalism</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/feeds/dart.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://boustrophedon.github.io/</id><updated>2014-09-12T02:24:25-04:00</updated><entry><title>This will make some people mad</title><link href="https://boustrophedon.github.io/this-will-make-some-people-mad.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-12T02:24:25-04:00</updated><author><name>Harry Stern</name></author><id>tag:boustrophedon.github.io,2014-09-12:this-will-make-some-people-mad.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the shower today I came up with a pretty good metaphor for javascript vs. dart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You live in a desert. It is a no-fun, boring place. One day, someone from the Eich Construction Co. decides to make a playground. However, instead of a playground they end up making a minefield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone rejoices and declares this to be the best thing ever. About 10-15 years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People spend their time navigating the minefield, learning all the quirks and blowing themselves up regularly. Some people write books about how to navigate it (The Good Parts), others try to carpet or paint over the parts that are unsafe (CoffeeScript, TypeScript). People acquire Stockholm Syndrome regarding the playground/minefield and try to convince other people how fun it is.
"Oh, avoiding the mines is a great way to increase your acrobatic ability."
"You know, if you squint closely the minefield has some characteristics of a &lt;em&gt;functional&lt;/em&gt; playground."
"Look at this sandcastle I build directly on top of an active mine! I'm sure there won't be any problems if I try and make it bigger."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people even take some of the mines and put them in their own &lt;strike&gt;servers&lt;/strike&gt; backyards and claim it is the best thing since sliced bread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then this company GOOG Development Inc. comes along and some of them see these people being blown up, and decide to try something new. They build this nice big platform above the minefield, so you can't even step on it unless you really want to. It has actual attractions, like a water slide and a merry-go-round, because GOOG Dev. Inc. has lots of money to throw around. They develop a home version so you can put it in your &lt;strike&gt;server&lt;/strike&gt; backyard and it is faster and more efficient in benchmarks than the original mines. (okay I gave up on the metaphor here)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's really nice, but people have learned to love their minefield and continue to tell themselves that it's great. Why? WHY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I couldn't think of a good way to fit it in, but the guys who developed the v8 engine that node runs on and such? they are the guys who started dart and made the dart vm faster than v8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this sparks lots of flame wars in the Hackathon Hackers group.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Dart"></category><category term="Dartlang"></category><category term="Javascript"></category><category term="jimmies being rustled"></category></entry></feed>